[♪ opening theme song playing]
[KEN] To have a sister
and a best friend
you've trusted your whole life,
and to find out
they're imposters...
If that were me,
I probably wouldn't be able
to leave my room
for an entire month.
[HANA] I know, right?
Might be hard to get him
to trust us now, too.
Man, I hope not. I don't want
things to be awkward between us.
No skin off my back.
I couldn't care less
if this creates
a little distance.
I hate kids.
[KEN] Does that mean
Ms. Hana hates me, too?
♪
Now, can't allow this
to get cold.
One second.
This should cover food
for this month.
Oh, I almost forgot.
Thank you for the offering.
Are you sure
you don't need extra
since I'm not paying rent?
You're 13. You're already
helping more than you should.
Actually, on that note,
you should probably be
in school.
What's the plan?
Uh, do you need us to
help you transfer to one nearby?
Right. Yeah, I guess so.
[Hana moans]
Hm?
Don't wanna do school?
[Jiro groans]
Do you think that you'd be able
to teach me how to use a weapon?
I... want to get stronger.
[HANA] Hm...
[slurping]
Well, if you don't want to,
I won't make you.
Uh, what?
Education's important,
but school isn't the only way.
I'm sure you can learn
without it.
If you talk to people
in my line of work,
you'll find lots of them
took shortcuts.
[KEN] Uh, is that really okay?
All of us Higashi Village folks
have been ousted from society.
You gotta make do
with what you can get.
Now, come on.
You wanna be stronger,
you gotta eat.
Most fights are won
by bodyweight alone.
Not gonna get big
unless you eat big.
Thanks, Hana.
[Jiro whines]
[KEN] You know, I feel like
you're always eating a ton
and yet you're still so small.
[HANA] Yeah, doesn't it suck?
I keep trying to bulk up.
[Asa (fake) breathes nervously]
-Brother--
-Excuse me, what was that?
Who're you calling "brother?"
There's only one person
who gets to call him that,
and that would be me!
[Yuru groans]
Sorry, she's been
calling him that for so long,
it's habit.
Please forgive her, Asa.
[DANJI (TSUGAI)]
I'm so glad to see
you're all right, partner.
The moment that
I sensed you down here,
I was worried
the worst was gonna happen.
[ASA (FAKE)]
I'm sorry I made you worry.
[cries]
All those years...
they told me that you had
to stay locked in the cage
in order
to keep the village safe.
I thought it was normal,
that it's what
the village needed.
I just assumed
that's how it worked
and never thought to doubt it.
Sorry. With a little hindsight,
it obviously
doesn't make any sense.
It's insane. Who would keep
a cute little kid in a cell?
Oh, she's cute?
Well, why do you think that is?
It's because
she was copying yours truly.
[BOTH]
Why is she focused on that?
[ASA] Hold the phone!
So you're basically saying
I'm adorable, too!
Say it again!
No way! Shut your trap.
There's no need to hide
how much you love me!
Give your cute little sister
a hug!
Gods, you know you're a real
pain in the butt sometimes?
Hmm, I'm so sorry.
I shouldn't have lied
to my brother.
He's not your brother.
[ASA (FAKE)] I'm sorry,
please, I'm so sorry!
So what do you want me
to call you,
if "brother" doesn't work?
Uh, just "Yuru" should be fine.
[ASA (FAKE)] I'm sorry
for deceiving you, really.
For keeping you chained
to the village.
It was wrong. I knew that,
but I kept doing it.
You were always so nice to me.
You came to visit me every day.
We'd talk about everything.
I loved it so.
[cries]
I wished life would
never have to change.
Forever and ever,
I wanted
to keep being your sister.
[cries]
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
I'm sorry.
[YURU] There's no need for you
to copy her anymore.
I would like to see
who you really are.
[ASA (FAKE)] Huh?
[whimpers]
Uh? So tiny.
[chuckles] You're even smaller.
Tell me, what's your name?
What do you mean?
Ms. Kyoka must've called you
something, didn't she?
Kiri.
She named me
after the pretty flowers
that bloom
on the village's mountain.
"Kiri."
That's a good name.
And she said "Danji's" fitting
for a masculine son,
just like me!
Well, yeah. It means "boy."
-So you ready?
-[KIRI] Mm.
We'll tell you the truth.
At least everything we know.
[bird screeching]
[DANJI (TSUGAI)]
A long time ago,
Higashi was a stronghold.
There were smaller castles
around it,
each one with a village
of its own.
In one of those hamlets,
we were
the local Zashiki-Warashi,
enshrined to bring them
good luck.
We passed between a few masters,
but they were all simple
and real kind.
♪
Though small, that village
held nothing but our love.
They say some divine daemons
called Left and Right
live up there!
[KIRI] Oh, yes?
I wanna meet them.
[MAN 1] A big war's brewing.
I hear the lord of Higashi
went into battle himself!
[WOMAN]
But who are they against?
[MAN 2] We've been
ordered to send
some of our strongest young men.
They said they need
more fighters.
[DANJI (TSUGAI)] That was
the first time we heard
about that war.
It must have been about
400 years ago.
Kids, great news.
I've been chosen to go to war
alongside the lord of our land.
I'll make sure
to do you two proud
and come back
with heaps of riches.
We wanna go wherever you go.
We can be helpful.
Oh, I appreciate the thought,
but war is too dangerous
for the likes of you.
-[KIRI] Aw...
-But we would like to come, too.
[MASTER] I'll be fine,
but if anything did happen,
you'd become stray daemons.
So let's end our contract.
And you can wait for me
as relics.
Then we'll start a new contract
as soon as I get back.
How about it?
Would you two become
my daemons again?
Of course we will!
I can hardly wait!
Come back with stories!
♪
[DANJI (TSUGAI)]
So we returned to relics
and waited patiently
in our box,
until our master
would come home.
Eventually, we heard
through passersby
that the war was over.
In the end, the East prevailed.
[ASA] A war 400 years ago
that the East won.
-The Battle of Sekigahara?
-[BOTH] Mm?
Wait, you've heard
about this fight?
Is "Sekigahara"
what they call it here?
Yeah. It was a historic battle
that happened right around
the time you said.
Whoa. Really?
The Tokugawa shogunate
ruled the land after that.
They held power for 200 years.
You said the lord of Higashi
at the time
was fighting in that war.
I've never even heard
someone mention that.
Seems strange
that it's not a bigger part
of the village's history
if he won.
We never heard anything either.
You're right,
not even about any lands
he won for the village.
Maybe he did something
bad enough to be taboo.
[both gasp]
[ASA] Now that's been said,
maybe it was nothing
and he just wasn't noteworthy.
What did your previous master
tell you?
He must have known
since he went to war.
Did he mention it?
[BOTH] Mm...
[DANJI (TSUGAI)]
Our old master never came home.
[BOTH] Uh?
[DANJI (TSUGAI)] We wanted to
renew our contract with him
like we said, so we waited...
And waited...
And waited, and waited.
Over time, the voices
around us began to fade.
We knew we had been forgotten.
♪
Our little hamlet was gone.
Everyone had abandoned it.
- [footsteps]
- As the years wasted away,
we thought we'd waste away
with them,
never to form a contract
with a human again,
until one day...
[MAN] Oh, there you are.
The legend was true.
Must've been lonely in there.
Come with me.
[DANJI (TSUGAI)]
A kind young man
heard a legend about
some Zashiki-Warashi in the area
and followed it
until he tracked us down.
You know him.
The Higashi Village retainer,
Roei.
Hey, I do know that name.
That's the previous Tadera!
Uh-huh. Also Dera's pa.
Oh, so they're related?
Mr. Roei took us straight to
our new home in Higashi Village.
That's where we met her,
who we call "Ma,"
our master, Kyoka.
She'd lost both her husband
and her two children
in a terrible landslide.
She couldn't even
get out of bed.
In some small way,
Roei wanted to help
fill the hole in her heart.
He brought us together
and instructed her on how
to form a contract with us.
♪
You must be our new master!
You should give us names,
-whatever you think fits.
-Uh? Uh...
Tell me, I've heard stories,
but are these kids
what they call daemons?
[ROEI] Yep.
I thought they were legends
for children.
Do you want to play with us?
We're gonna stay
by your side forever and a day.
[BOTH] Master.
[chuckles]
Thank you, dears.
[DANJI (TSUGAI)]
She seemed sad, but also happy.
[YAMAHA]
Oh, my, those are daemons.
Some Zashiki-Warashi?
They'll bring you good fortune.
Say, Kyoka,
once you're feeling well enough
to be back on your feet,
I'd like you to come
to the keep and work for me.
So that old lady,
she could see us
without us having to let her.
Is she a Daemon Wielder, too?
Uh, could most people
not see these two?
[ROEI] Only Daemon Wielders,
anyone who the daemons choose
to reveal themselves to,
and a few others who just happen
to have the sense.
Me, for instance?
I've got my own pair
down the mountain.
Who was that old lady, master?
That's Granny Yamaha,
the leader of the village.
She's the oldest person
here by far.
She claims not even she
can remember how old she is.
-[wind howling]
-[bird cawing]
[breathes heavily]
[DANJI (TSUGAI)] A short time
after Ma started at the keep,
an outsider wandered
into the village.
Her name was Nagisa.
[breathes heavily]
[cow moos]
[DANJI (TSUGAI)]
The way she dressed...
It was nothing like
what we wore in the mountains.
That's how we knew she was
from the modern world.
[Nagisa panting]
[DANJI (TSUGAI)]
When they told her
she couldn't leave,
she became horribly depressed.
Mr. Mine felt sorry for her
and did everything
he could to help.
[MINE] Miss Nagisa?
[Nagisa yelps]
I thought we could
have some boar stew.
It'll cheer you up.
[Nagisa breathes uneasily]
[NAGISA] Wow, that is so grody.
So what? "Grody?"
[Nagisa laughs]
Never mind. And you know what?
I do feel a little better now.
[laughs]
[both chuckle]
♪
[DANJI (TSUGAI)]
Later, Yuru and Asa were born.
And something
in the villagers' eyes changed.
Because we didn't come
from there,
we didn't know
Higashi's whole history.
Of course, we heard legends...
...about the Break
and Seal twins. But...
[Kyoka grunts]
In the face
of unimaginable power,
people lose their humanity.
[DANJI (TSUGAI)] We could tell
Ma had pretty serious opinions
about it,
but she never went into detail.
[rustling]
[chirping]
[AZAMI'S MOM] Seal's here.
Break, too.
What's taking the bandits
so long?
They should hurry.
How long must we wait
until Higashi Village
reigns supreme?
Hey, Mommy?
What are you talking about?
Nothing, Azami.
Go back to sleep.
♪
[Danji (younger) sighs]
-[hoofbeats]
-[gasps]
-Yuru!
-Mm?
Are you going out hunting?
I'll join!
I'm fine, Danji.
Don't follow me.
But it's dangerous going into
the mountains all by yourself!
[YURU] You're just trying
to slack off your work
in the fields!
[DANJI] Aw, you got me.
DANJI (TSUGAI) After that,
you know everything.
Our ma got an order
from Granny Yamaha.
She needed Kiri
to impersonate Asa.
But that wasn't all.
Ma told me to watch over you
and to make sure Granny
never found out.
[Yuru grunts]
If you don't mind, I'd like
to send you out there before us.
I want to chat
with my sister in private.
[Asa gasps] By ourselves?
Our first heart-to-heart
since we were kids!
Could you quit being weird
and kick these two out?
Hey, Yin and Yang?
Let the Zashiki-Warashi out,
but keep my brother and me here!
[DANJI (TSUGAI)]
Yuru, one thing.
I know you're mad at your sister
for attacking
the village that day,
but she didn't actually
kill anyone herself.
Our ma got bruised up
by some rubble,
but that was the worst thing
she did to any of the villagers!
[Yuru grunts]
Don't let him make you think
I'm a saint.
The only reason
I didn't kill anyone
is 'cause I didn't have to.
If I even suspect
someone's a threat to the people
who are important to me,
I'll show no mercy.
You know,
you haven't lied to me once
since we were reunited,
and I want to acknowledge that.
There were some things
that must've been hard to say,
but you were still
perfectly honest.
[ASA] I'm sorry, Yuru.
You said you were looking
for the innocent little sister
you knew.
I'm afraid
you'll never find her.
No.
She died that day.
So now, I wanna be honest
about how I feel, too.
In those 10 years
after our parents
fled the village, I struggled.
Danji and Kiri were my rocks
during that period.
They were my reason to live.
Whenever the weight
of being abandoned
felt like too much,
I had a sister and a best friend
to lean on.
Has that changed?
Now that I know they were fakes?
Does that mean
the strength they gave me
wasn't real, either?
I think it was real,
so I can't find it in me
to hate them.
[ASA] Hm.
-[exclaims]
-Huh?
Aw, man! This is so unfair!
I only got to spend six years
with you before I left.
How am I supposed
to compare to their 10?
And it gets even worse
when you consider we were babies
for part of that.
If we're only counting the years
we actually remember,
then we're looking at three,
maybe four at best.
[sighs]
It isn't fair.
♪
[Yuru sighs]
Well, now we're together again,
aren't we?
Anything you wanna do?
Like, right now?
No, like dreams for the future.
Oh, yeah!
I really wanna go to Disney!
To what? Dizzy?
I wanna buy tons
of cute stuffed animals,
enjoy all the rides and parades,
and take a picture
at Cinderella's castle...
[YURU] A castle?
So there's a lord?
Wonder what
the crop yield's like.
[Asa sighs]
I want to have fun
doing normal things.
Attend some school
and whine about studying
like a normal kid.
Talk about the hot boys
in class like a normal girl.
Complain about my boring job
on the commuter train
like a normal adult.
That's all.
I just want a normal life.
Good joke, right?
Like any of that's possible
in this kill or be killed
world we're in.
[YURU] When you think about
having this normal life,
are Mom, Dad, and I
a part of it?
Yeah!
Then we need
to build it together,
even if it takes us years.
We had 10 apart,
so what's 10 more?
We'll defeat all our enemies,
reunite with our mom and dad,
and live a life together
without needing to hide.
And that place... Diz-ay?
We'll go as a family!
We'll have fun at the castle!
Right!
And I learned something
you should know
about our parents.
Years ago,
someone had to teach Mom and Dad
how to get through the barrier
and escape from Higashi.
It was Roei.
Mm? So Dera's father
helped them?
Seriously? Mom and Dad
never mentioned
a word about him to me.
-Likely for his sake.
-Uh?
What he did was considered
a betrayal of Higashi.
So to repay him,
they chose to keep quiet.
Even to their own family.
It's not just Dera.
Roei has another son
down the mountain.
But neither of them
have any idea where he could be.
If there's any chance Roei still
has contact with our parents,
then tracking him down
may be our best lead.
[ASA] Mm.
You can count on Dera and me
to hunt his old man down.
Cool. Thank you for that.
Also, there's a Daemon Wielder
with katanas.
He claims to know what happened
to our parents
-when they disappeared.
-[gasps softly]
[ASA] Katanas?
[gasps] Ivan Yosano!
What did he say to you?
Our parents, where are they at?
-What does he know?
-Listen to me carefully, Asa.
Try not to panic.
He told me...
he killed Mom and Dad.
Ivan claimed he used the swords
he was wielding
to cut them both down.
-[breathing heavily]
-We wanted to ask more,
but he escaped before we could.
[continues breathing heavily]
Asa!
-Listen!
-No way. He killed them?
Calm down, Asa, please!
[tearfully]
Mom and Dad, they're really...
This is my fault.
It's because they took me away
from the village.
They were dragged into this
'cause I was born.
Asa, focus!
Just because he said it
doesn't mean that it's true!
You can't believe him.
The whole world is filled
with people you shouldn't trust.
Don't believe it until you've
seen it with your own eyes.
You said yourself that
Mom and Dad were alive and well!
You believed that!
Just breathe... Exhale slowly.
[exhales]
What was I thinking?
They've gotta be out there,
somewhere.
That's right. And if anyone's
trying to hold them captive,
we'll just bust them out!
Then we'll go.
The four of us.
Live a happy and normal life!
We'll start with those katanas.
I'll use Break to dissolve
their contract with him.
And Yuru...
Next time you find him,
do whatever you can
to lure him towards me.
It doesn't matter
how far away he is.
Soon as he enters my sight,
he's done for.
[YURU] Good.
Left and Right
are already familiar
with the scent of his blood.
We'll lure, but we'll leave
the real hunt to you!
[ASA] Hm.
[♪ closing theme song playing]
[GONZO] Good evening, ma'am.
[NATSUKI] Destroyed?
[AKIO] I didn't understand
the pain of others.
I felt an emotion
I'd never felt before.